<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sysadmin on J&#39;aime pas les piles</title>
    <link>https://blog.bapt.name/tags/sysadmin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sysadmin on J&#39;aime pas les piles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under WTFPL.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 14:36:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.bapt.name/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Nitrokey Pro and Fido2</title>
      <link>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/07/09/using-nitrokey-pro-and-fido2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 14:36:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/07/09/using-nitrokey-pro-and-fido2/</guid>
      <description>In order to store and protect my credentials and to simplify 2 Factor authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve bought some USB keys from Nitrokey.
While it may be possible to find more complete or fancy solutions I selected Nitrokey, a German company, as both hardware and software is Open Source and I trust this way more than a black box provided by a company that is asking to get some blind trust.
For storing and protecting GPG or S/MIME key I&amp;rsquo;ve choosed a Nitrokey Pro 2 USB key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archlinux cleaning installed packages groups with Pacman</title>
      <link>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/05/01/archlinux-cleaning-installed-packages-groups-with-pacman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 10:37:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/05/01/archlinux-cleaning-installed-packages-groups-with-pacman/</guid>
      <description>On Archlinux pacman allows to install packages as a group. Cleaning those packages and their dependencies is not as straight forward, but it possible to do cleaning by using a few commands.
Here let&amp;rsquo;s try to clean plasma stuff (finally I find gnome more straightforward to used, despite being sometimes a bit surprised by the lack of customisation or by some choices.)
# Check installed packages from groups pacman -Qg # Collect installed list of packages for specific groups pacman -Qgq plasma &amp;gt; plasma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring with Sensu</title>
      <link>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/04/25/monitoring-with-sensu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 15:56:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.bapt.name/2020/04/25/monitoring-with-sensu/</guid>
      <description>Some notes taken during a deployment of Sensu with one backend server and some nodes running agents.
Installing Sensu Follow the official documentation.
Installing the backend # Add the Sensu repository curl -s https://packagecloud.io/install/repositories/sensu/stable/script.rpm.sh | sudo bash # Install the sensu-go-backend package sudo yum install sensu-go-backend # Copy the config template from the docs sudo curl -L https://docs.sensu.io/sensu-go/latest/files/backend.yml -o /etc/sensu/backend.yml # Start sensu-backend sudo systemctl enable --now sensu-backend # Initialise sudo systemctl status -l sensu-backend export SENSU_BACKEND_CLUSTER_ADMIN_USERNAME=YOUR_USERNAME export SENSU_BACKEND_CLUSTER_ADMIN_PASSWORD=YOUR_PASSWORD sensu-backend init # Check that backend replies curl http://127.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
